A Guide to the Historical Photograph Collection (List of Subjects) 1890s-present
Special Collections, Virginia Tech
Special Collections, Virginia Tech
Historical Photograph Collection (List of Subjects), 1890s-present
Special Collections, Virginia Tech, Blacksburg, Va.
Photographs.001
55.5 cu. ft. 61 boxes; 12 oversize boxes
The photograph collection at Special Collections consists primarily of historical photographs of Virginia Tech, dating back to the 1890s. The collection is also home to historic images of Blacksburg, Montgomery County, the New River Valley, and Southwest Virginia in general. A photograph collection of faculty and staff from the university is maintained separately.
Administrative Information
Access Restrictions
Collection is open for research.
Acquisition Information
The Historical Photograph Collection consists primarily of images donated or transferred to the University Libraries and/or the University Archives over time.
Scope and Content
The photograph collection at Special Collections consists primarily of historical photographs of Virginia Tech, dating back to the 1890s. Subjects include, but are not limited to: athletics, the Corps of Cadets, campus views and buildings, events and celebrations, Agricultural Extension sites/work, and candid images of students and campus groups. A alphabetically organized photograph collection of faculty and staff from the university is maintained separately.
The collection is also home to historic images of Blacksburg, Montgomery County, the New River Valley, and Southwest Virginia in general. Subjects include, but are not limited to: historic sites and buildings, Blacksburg views and buildings, scenes from surrounding towns/cities/counties, agriculture activities, and candid images of people.
Arrangement
The collection is arranged alphabetically by subject. Each subject listed has at least one photograph; some subjects have multiple folders.
Adjunct Descriptive Data
Related Materials
Faculty/Staff Photograph Collection
Individual Photograph Collections (usually named for the subject matter or collector)
Index Terms
Subjects:
Agricultural extension work; Blacksburg (Va.); Local/Regional History and Appalachian South; Montgomery County (Va.); University History; Virginia Agricultural and Mechanical College; Virginia Agricultural and Mechanical College and Polytechnic Institute; Virginia Polytechnic Institute; Virginia Polytechnic Institute and State University; Virginia Polytechnic Institute and State University. Corps of Cadets
Historical Photograph Collection (List of Subjects)
- ACADEMIC BUILDINGS, FIRST AND SECOND
- ADMINISTRATION BUILDING
- ADMINISTRATION BUILDING (OLD) (Housed administration offices from 1904 to 1936; also known as Rock House and Alwood House).
- AFRICAN-AMERICAN INDIVIDUALS
- AFRICAN-AMERICAN STUDENTS
- AGNEW HALL
- AGRICULTURAL EDUCATION BUILDING
- Agricultural Hall -- see PRICE HALL
- AGRICULTURE
- AIR FORCE - RANDOLPH FIELD
- AIRPLANES (see also AIRPORT, AVIATION)
- AIRPORT (see also AIRPLANES, AVIATION)
- ALUMNI (individuals; arranged alphabetically)
- ALUMNI GATES
- ALUMNI - GROUPS
- ALUMNI HALL
- Alumni Mall -- see MALL
- ALUMNI, NOTED
- ALUMNI - PRESS PRINTS (Small prints of unidentified individual alumni)
- AMBLER JOHNSTON HALL
- Amphitheatre -- see GARDEN AMPHITHEATRE
- ANAEROBE LAB
- ANGLE FLIGHT
- ANIMALS
- Apollo Club -- see GLEE CLUB
- APPLE PACKING HOUSE
- ARCHITECTURE DEPT. - College of Architecture and Urban Studies
- ARCHWAYS
- ARMISTICE DAY
- ARMY SPECIALIZED TRAINING PROGRAM (ASTP)
- ART
- ART INVENTORY
- ATHLETIC ASSOCIATION
- ATHLETIC COUNCIL
- Athletics -- see SPORTS and/or specific name of sport
- AUDIO VISUAL EQUIPMENT
- AVIATION (see also AIRPORT, AIRPLANES)
- AWARDS AND CITATIONS
- BABCOCK AND WILCOX
- BAND (see also HIGHTY TIGHTIES, MARCHING VIRGINIANS, MUSIC)
- BARBER SHOP
- BARNS
- BARRACKS
- BARRINGER HALL
- BASEBALL - PRE-1900
- BASEBALL - 1900-20
- BASEBALL - 1920-40
- BASEBALL - 1940-50
- BASEBALL - 1950-60
- BASEBALL - 1960-70
- BASEBALL - 1970-80
- BASEBALL - 1980-present
- BASKETBALL - 1908-20
- BASKETBALL - 1920-40
- BASKETBALL - 1940-50
- BASKETBALL - 1950-60
- BASKETBALL - 1960-70
- BASKETBALL - 1970-80
- BASKETBALL - 1980-present
- BASKETBALL - 1973 NIT FINALS
- BASKETBALL - 1994-95 NIT
- BASKETBALL - WOMEN'S
- BATTALION
- BICYCLISTS
- BIOCHEMISTRY BUILDING
- BLACK, EDWARD, FARM
- Black Students -- see AFRICAN AMERICAN STUDENTS
- BLACKSBURG - BUSINESSES AND INDUSTRY - PRE-1900
- BLACKSBURG - BUSINESSES AND INDUSTRY - 1900-19
- BLACKSBURG - BUSINESSES AND INDUSTRY - 1920-39
- BLACKSBURG - BUSINESSES AND INDUSTRY - 1940-59
- BLACKSBURG - BUSINESSES AND INDUSTRY - 1960-present
- BLACKSBURG - CHURCHES - pre-1900
- BLACKSBURG - CHURCHES - 1900-19
- BLACKSBURG - CHURCHES - 1920-39
- BLACKSBURG - CHURCHES - 1940-59
- BLACKSBURG - CHURCHES - 1960-present
- BLACKSBURG - DOWNTOWN - pre-1900
- BLACKSBURG - DOWNTOWN - 1900-19
- BLACKSBURG - DOWNTOWN - 1920-39
- BLACKSBURG - DOWNTOWN - 1940-59
- BLACKSBURG - DOWNTOWN - 1960-
- BLACKSBURG - HOUSES - PRE-1900
- BLACKSBURG - HOUSES - 1900-19
- BLACKSBURG - HOUSES - 1920-39
- BLACKSBURG - HOUSES - 1940-59
- BLACKSBURG - HOUSES - 1960-present
- BLACKSBURG - PEOPLE - pre-1900
- BLACKSBURG - PEOPLE - 1900-19
- BLACKSBURG - PEOPLE - 1920-39
- BLACKSBURG - SCHOOLS - 1920-39
- BLACKSBURG - SCHOOLS - 1940-59
- BLACKSBURG - VIEWS - PRE-1900
- BLACKSBURG - VIEWS - 1900-19
  Note
  Poster-sized photographs of Blacksburg from this time period are available for viewing in Special Collections (Special Collections staff look in ART/Drawer 1 and Drawer 2).
- BLACKSBURG - VIEWS - 1920-39
- BLACKSBURG - VIEWS - 1940-59
- BLACKSBURG - PICTORIAL BROCHURES
- BLANKET TOSSES
- BLOODMOBILE
- BOARD OF VISITORS
- BOOKSTORE (Old; in Barracks No. 1)
- BOXING
- BRODIE HALL
- BROOKS FOREST PRODUCTS CENTER
- BUGLE - 1922 COLLECTION (Some of the photographs used in 1922 Bugle (the Virginia Tech student yearbook))
- BUGLE - 1937 COLLECTION (Some of the photographs used in the 1937 Bugle (the Virginia Tech student yearbook))
- BUGLE - 1959 COLLECTION (Some of the photographs used in the 1959 Bugle (the Virginia Tech student yearbook))
- BUGLE - 1960 COLLECTION (Some of the photographs used in the 1960 Bugle (the Virginia Tech student yearbook))
- BUILDING CONSTRUCTION
- BUILDING DEDICATIONS
- BUILDING DETAILS (see also ARCHWAYS)
- BUILDINGS (see also names of specific building)
- BUILDINGS, CAMPUS (UNIDENTIFIED)
- BUILDINGS - 1931 INSURANCE SURVEY PHOTOGRAPHS (Photographs taken of buildings in 1931 for insurance purposes. A list of the buildings can be found in the front of the folder.)
- BUILDINGS, UNIDENTIFIED
- BURRUSS HALL
- BUSINESS CLASSES
- CAMPBELL HALL
- CAMPUS AERIALS - (subdivided by decade: 1950-59, 1960-69, 1970-79
- CAMPUS ENTRANCE
- Campus life -- see STUDENTS
- CAMPUS MAPS - 1908-39
- CAMPUS MAPS - 1940-49
- CAMPUS MAPS - 1950-69
- CAMPUS MAPS - 1960-69
- CAMPUS MAPS - 1970-79
- CAMPUS MAPS - 1980-
- CAMPUS PICTORIAL BROCHURES
- CAMPUS SCENES (includes people and activities; see also STUDENTS, CAMPUS WINTER SCENES)
- CAMPUS VIEWS - NO DATES (includes buildings and physical environs)
- CAMPUS VIEWS - 1870-1880s
- CAMPUS VIEWS - 1880-89
- CAMPUS VIEWS - 1890-99
- CAMPUS VIEWS - 1900-09
- CAMPUS VIEWS - 1910-19
- CAMPUS VIEWS - 1920-29
- CAMPUS VIEWS - 1930-39
- CAMPUS VIEWS - 1940-49
- CAMPUS VIEWS - 1950-59
- CAMPUS VIEWS - 1960-69
- CAMPUS VIEWS - 1970-79
- CAMPUS VIEWS - 1980-89
- CAMPUS WINTER SCENES
- CANNON
- CASCADES
- CASSELL COLISEUM
- CEC -- see CONTINUING EDUCATION CENTER
- CENTENNIAL--VIRGINIA TECH (1972)
- CENTENNIAL ISSUE (MONTGOMERY NEWS MESSENGER) (Eleven photographs of other colleges used for a special edition of the Montgomery News Messenger.)
- Chapel (Old) -- see LIBRARY (OLD)
- CHAPEL (WAR MEMORIAL)
- CHEATHAM HALL
- CHEERLEADERS
- CHILDREN
- CHRISTIANSBURG
- CLASSES AND CLASS REUNIONS (chronological by graduation year)
- CLASSROOMS
- CLUBS
- COACHES
- COAL MINES
- COCHRANE HALL
- Coliseum -- see CASSELL COLISEUM
- College of Education -- see EDUCATION, COLLEGE OF
- COLLEGIANS (see also MUSIC)
- COLORS
- COMMANDANTS
- COMMANDANT'S HOUSE
- COMMENCEMENT
- COMMENCEMENT HALL
- COMMERCE HALL
- Commissioning Ceremonies -- see CORPS - COMMISSIONING
- CONCERTS
- CONTINUING EDUCATION CENTER (CEC)
- CORPS
- CORPS - BATTERY E
- CORPS - COMPANY A
- CORPS - COMPANY B
- CORPS - COMPANY C
- CORPS - COMPANY D
- CORPS - COMPANY E
- CORPS - COMPANY F
- CORPS - COMPANY G
- CORPS - COMPANY H
- CORPS - COMMISSIONING
- CORPS - INDIVIDUALS
- CORPS - OFFICERS
- CORPS - WOMEN
- COTILLION CLUB
- COWGILL HALL
- CRAIG HEALING SPRINGS
- CREAMERY
- CROSS COUNTRY
- DAIRY HUSBANDRY BUILDING
- DANCES
- DAVIDSON HALL
- DERRING HALL
- DIETRICK DINING HALL
- DINING HALL - INTERIOR SHOTS
- DIPLOMAS
- DIVERSITY
- Donaldson Brown CED -- see CONTINUING EDUCATION CENTER (CEC)
- DORMITORIES
- DORMITORY ROOMS
- DRAPER CABIN / DRAPER'S MEADOW
- DRILL FIELD
- DRILL HALL
- DUCK POND
- EDUCATION, COLLEGE OF
- EGGLESTON HALL
- EGGLESTON SPRINGS
- ELECTRICAL LABORATORY
- ENGEL HALL
- ENGINEERING
- EQUESTRIAN
- Equine Medical Center -- see MARION DUPONT SCOTT EQUINE MEDICAL CENTER
- EXTENDED CAMPUS
- EXTENSION
- EXTENSION BUILDING
- FACULTY (filed separately, alphabetical by name)
- FACULTY APARTMENTS
- FACULTY CENTER
- FACULTY AND STAFF HOUSES
- FACULTY, MILITARY
- FACULTY ROW
- FACULTY SENATE
- FARM BUILDINGS (see also BARNS)
- FEMOYER HALL
- FENCING
- FIELD HOCKEY
- FIELD HOUSE (OLD)
- FIELD HOUSE (RECTOR)
- FINALS
- FIRE DRILLS
- FIRES
- FLOOD (1943)
- FOOD SCIENCE BUILDINGS
- FOOD SCIENCE DEPT.
- FOOTBALL - 1890s
- FOOTBALL - 1900-10
- FOOTBALL - 1910-20
- FOOTBALL - 1920-30
- FOOTBALL - 1930-40
- FOOTBALL - 1940-50
- FOOTBALL - 1950-60
- FOOTBALL - 1960-70
- FOOTBALL - 1970-80
- FOOTBALL - 1980-90
- FOOTBALL - INDIVIDUALS (arranged alphabetically by name)
- FORESTRY AND WILDLIFE
- FORT BELVOIR
- FORT HUMPHRIES
- FORT MONROE ROTC CAMP
- FOUNDER'S DAY
- FOUR-H
- FRATERNITIES -- see SORORITIES AND FRATERNITIES
- FRIENDS OF THE UNIVERSITY LIBRARIES
- GARDEN AMPHITHEATRE
- GEOLOGY
- GERMAN CLUB
- GIBBONEY FIELD
- GLEE CLUB (see also MUSIC)
- GOLDEN JUBILEE (1922)
- GOLF
- GOVERNOR'S DAY
- GRADUATION
- GRAY JACKET
- GREENHOUSES
- GROUPS SHOTS (MISCELLANEOUS)
- GUBERNATORIAL VISITS TO CAMPUS
- Gymnasium -- see WAR MEMORIAL GYMNASIUM
- GYMNASTICS
- HANCOCK HALL
- HENDERSON HALL (see also INFIRMARY, HOSPITAL)
- HIGHTY-TIGHTIES (see also BAND, MUSIC)
- HILLCREST
- HOLDEN HALL
- HOLLINS INSTITUTE
- HOME ECONOMICS
- HOME ECONOMICS LAB
- HOMECOMING
- HORSE SHOW
- HORTICULTURAL HALL
- HORTICULTURE
- Hospital -- see HENDERSON HALL
- HUCKLEBERRY
- HUTCHESON HALL
- INDIVIDUALS (see also FACULTY and names of specific individuals and groups)
- INDUSTRIAL ARTS PROGRAMS
- INFIRMARY (see also Henderson Hall)
- INGLES CABIN
- JAMESTOWN EXPOSITION
- JOHNSON HALL
- Johnston Hall -- see AMBLER JOHNSTON HALL
- KENTLAND
- LABORATORIES (Bio, Cardiac, Soils, Vet Med)
- LACROSSE
- LANE HALL (see also BARRACKS)
- LANE STADIUM
- LAUNDRY
- LAVERY, WILLIAM
- LEARNING RESOURCES CENTER (LRC) TV - early 1980s
- LEE HALL
- LEE, ROBERT E.
- Library (New) -- see NEWMAN LIBRARY
- LIBRARY (OLD) (see also LIBRARY STAFF)
- LIBRARY STAFF
- LOVERS' LANE
- LOVERS' LEAP
- LYRIC THEATRE
- McBRYDE BUILDING (1914-66) (see also MECHANIC ARTS BUILDING)
- McBRYDE FAMILY
- McBRYDE HALL
- McCOMAS HALL
- McCORMICK DAY
- McCORMICK FARM
  Oversize McCormick Farm photographs (on wood boards) and in boxes are available in Special Collections (Special Collections staff look on MR/3/A5 and in ART/Drawer 1).
- MABRY MILL
- MACHINE SHOPS
- MAIN WALK
- Major Williams Hall -- see WILLIAMS HALL
- MALL
- MARCHING VIRGINIANS
- MARION DUPONT SCOTT EQUINE MEDICAL CENTER
- MAROON MASK
- MASCOTS
- MAURY LITERARY SOCIETY
- MAY DAY
- MECHANIC ARTS BUILDING (see also McBRYDE BUILDING)
- MECHANICAL LAB
- MEDAL OF HONOR WINNERS
- Memorial Chapel -- see CHAPEL (WAR MEMORIAL)
- MERRIMAC MINES
- MESS HALL
- MILES HALL
- MILES STADIUM
- MILITARY DEMONSTRATIONS
- MILITARY LABORATORY
- MILITARY SPRING MANEUVERS (1942)
- MILITARY STAFF
- MINERAL BUILDING
- MINING HALL
- MINSTRELS
- MISCELLANEOUS
- MONOGRAM CLUB
- MONTGOMERY COUNTY
- MOUNTAIN LAKE
- MUSIC (see also BAND, COLLEGIANS, GLEE CLUB, HIGHTY TIGHTIES, MARCHING VIRGINIANS)
- NASA
- NAVY V-12 STUDENTS
- NEW RIVER
- NEW RIVER COMMUNITY COLLEGE
- NEW RIVER VALLEY
- NEW VIRGINIANS
- NEWMAN HALL
- NEWMAN LIBRARY (see also FRIENDS OF THE UNIVERSITY LIBRARIES, LIBRARY STAFF)
- NEWMAN LIBRARY ADDITION
- NEWMAN LIBRARY ADDITION - CONSTRUCTION
- NORRIS HALL
- NORFOLK AND WESTERN RAILWAY (For more railroad photographs, see the Norfolk and Western Historical Photograph Collection.)
- OFFICERS TRAINING CAMP (1918)
- OLD GUARD
- ONE HUNDRED TWENTY-FIFTH ANNIVERSARY
- O'SHAUGHNESSY HALL
- OWENS HALL
- PAMPLIN HALL
- PAN-AMERICAN EXPOSITION (1901)
- PARADES (see also RAT PARADES)
- PATTON HALL
- PAVILION
- PAYNE, CHARLES K.
- PEP RALLY
- PEPPER'S FERRY
- PERFORMING ARTS BUILDING (see also YMCA)
- PETERSBURG CLUB
- PILLOW FIGHTS
- POLITICIANS (Includes Jim Turn, John Dalton, Bob Bradford, Governor Godwin, Fred Pollard, Linwood Holten, and Richard M. Nixon.)
- POST OFFICE
- POULTRY BUILDING
- POWER MAGAZINE
- POWER PLANT
- PRESIDENT'S HOUSE HOMES
- PRESTON AND OLIN BUILDING
- PRICE HALL (formerly Agricultural Hall)
- PRITCHARD HALL
- PURGATORY PUPS
- QUADRANGLE
- QUARRY
- RACQUETBALL
- RADFORD
- RADIO (STUDENT)
- RANDOLPH HALL
- RASCHE DORMITORY
- RAT CLASSES
- RAT FUNERALS
- RAT PARADES
- Rector Field House -- see FIELD HOUSE (RECTOR)
- Rectors, Board of Visitors -- see BOARD OF VISITORS
- REGISTRATION
- RESTON CLASSROOM
- RIFLE TEAM
- RING DANCE
- ROANOKE, VIRGINIA
- ROBESON HALL
- "ROCK, THE" (MEMORIAL) (see also WORLD WAR I MEMORIAL)
- ROCKBRIDGE CLUB
- ROTC
- RUGBY
- ST. LOUIS [MISSOURI] WORLD'S FAIR (1904)
- SANDY HALL
- SATELLITE TRACKING STATION
- SAUNDERS HALL
- SCIENCE HALL
- SCRUBBING NUMERALS
- SEALS (UNIVERSITY)
- SEITZ HALL
- SHAM BATTLES
- SHANKS HALL
- SHIELDS
- SHOPS
- SHORT COURSES
- SHULTZ DINING HALL
- SLUSHER SIGNS/DISPLAYS/EXHIBITS
- SMITHFIELD PLANTATION
- SMYTH HALL
- SMYTH, J. ADGER
- SNOW BATTLES
- SOCCER
- SOLAR ENGINEERING
- SOLITUDE
- SOPHOMORE BANQUET
- SORORITIES AND FRATERNITIES
- SOUTHERN SEMINARY
- SOUTHWEST VIRGINIA
- SPECIAL EFFECTS
- SPECIAL EQUIPMENT
- SPORTS - INTERCOLLEGIATE, 1972-82
- SPORTS - INTRAMURAL
- SPORTS - MISC.
- SPORTS - OPPONENTS
- SQUIRES, ARTHUR
- SQUIRES STUDENT CENTER
- STEAM LAUNDRY (see also LAUNDRY)
- STONE DORMITORY
- Stone Quarry -- see QUARRY
- STORAGE LOTS
- STROUBLE'S CREEK
- STUDENT ACTIVITIES
- STUDENT ORGANIZATIONS
- STUDENT PUBLICATIONS
- STUDENT UNREST
- STUDENTS - 1872-99
- STUDENTS - 1900-30
- STUDENTS - 1930-50
- STUDENTS - 1950-60
- STUDENTS - 1960-70
- STUDENTS - 1968
- STUDENTS - 1970-80
- STUDENTS - 1980-present
- STUDENTS - MEN
- STUDENTS - WOMEN
- SURFACE, JOHN C.
- SWIMMING
- SWINE CENTER
- Tech Buccaneers -- see MUSIC
- TENNIS
- THEATRE
- THOMAS HALL
- TRACK - 1896-1910
- TRACK - 1911-30
- TRACK - 1930-60
- TRACK - 1960-
- TRAILERS
- UNIFORMS
- UNIVERSITY CLUB
- UPPER QUAD
- VAWTER HALL
- VETERINARY SCIENCE BUILDING
- VIP'S
- VIRGINIA POULTRY CLUBS
- VIRGINIA SOCIETY OF PROFESSIONAL ENGINEERS
- Virginia Water Resources Research Center -- see WATER RESOURCES RESEARCH CENTER
- VISITING SCHOLAR PROGRAM
- VOLLEYBALL
- WALKING OFF DEMERITS
- WALLACE HALL
- War Memorial Chapel -- see CHAPEL (WAR MEMORIAL)
- WAR MEMORIAL GYMNASIUM
- WATER RESOURCES RESEARCH CENTER
- WATER TOWER
- WEIGHT LIFTING
- WESLEY FOUNDATION
- WHITE SULPHUR SPRINGS (Virginia)
- WHITETHORNE
- WHITTEMORE HALL
- WILLIAM PRESTON SOCIETY
- WILLIAMS HALL
- WILSON, JOHN D.
- WIND TUNNEL
- WINE AWARD
- WINTER SCENES
- Women Students -- see STUDENTS - WOMEN
- WORKING - WORKERS AND WORK SITES - AT VIRGINIA TECH
- WORLD WAR I MONUMENT (see also "ROCK, THE")
- WRESTLING
- YMCA
- YELLOW SULPHUR SPRINGS